The snow's got a bite out here.
Now they're hunting me.
[Carja villager]
We're letting the…
…Oseram decide what to do with him?
[Carja villager]
But he tried to kill our Sun-King!
[Carja outlander]
It was Dervahl…
I'm gonna need you.
That wasn't a warning.
It's a clever trick they have, but no need to see what you can scent.
This blood is sharp, huntress, flint-sharp!
[laughs]
The last time I took it in to me,
they say I slept the sleep of death and sweated dark oil.
Alright, try not to die.
A Stalker, watching us!
Watched by us.
In red eyes, I thought to see ourselves reflected.
No, they were dull and set.
Set with a purpose precise from their machine-mother foundries.
They prey.
They will not flinch.
They are indifferent to the wild. They are … final.
They are weapons, that's all.
My heart drops.
Why look for understanding in the axe the moment before it splits your skull?
No. No, no, no, no, no, there's more.
The axe does not remember its smelting.
These machines do, and pine for the Metal World.
It's hard to know what to make of you.
Then open my mouth and look inside!
[laughs]
A cave of echoes and memory, but not my own.
I mean, you're tough skinned, I'll give you that.
Especially on the inside.
I first drank at the spring of a fallen Thunderjaw.
The cables cried out like water birds.
But felling giants is short work for you.
Trying to appeal to my pride?
No.
To inevitability, huntress.
The tremor of their tread, can you feel it?
Tugging you to the Eastern Valleys?
So a Thunderjaw next, huh?
But of course.
Go where the hunt takes you, but…
[laughs]
…let the blood lead you back.
You're coming with me.
It'd be fascinating, if they weren't looking for me.
Whenever a machine falls, a Scrapper won't be far.
Makes this a little easier.
Here they come.
[Carja merchant]
…what do with him, but he tried to kill our Sun-King!
[Carja artisan]
The Oseram have gone too far this time. Dervahl…
[Carja merchant]
You'll like what I have for sale, I promise.
You're back.
I've gotten some reports, so I have a notion of what you're gonna say.
That your man Zaid was running a slaving operation right under your nose?
He was never my man, but I won't make excuses.
I should've dug harder for proof of his guilt.
There'll be a full investigation.
If you see this young woman again, assure her she'll face no reprisal.
And please offer her my personal apology.
Do you really think that will help her?
No, I don't suppose it will.
But for every shadow there's some light.
I hope you'll see that one day.
[Carja merchant]
Take a look at these wares.
I've got all the best goods here.
[Carja artisan]
She was incredible, stopped Dervahl without breaking a sweat.
[Oseram trader]
Nothing but trouble, that's all there is in Banuk lands.
I heard you talking about trouble in Banuk lands.
Was that out loud?
Ears must be getting worn down from all those Longleg blasts.
But you heard right.
I'm fresh back from The Cut looking for better scavenging and better shards.
I guess you didn't find them up there?
Not with the Banuk wailing about new machines,
and talking spirits, and their purses frozen shut.
What's a trade route without trade? It's just a route.
There's a trade route?
I thought the Banuk kept to themselves.
We Oseram and the Banuk are neighbours after all.
What's a few mountain ranges between friends?
I have some acquaintances out there,
still trying to dig a living out of the ice, but they say nothing seems to stick.
All the superstitious nonsense and rampaging machines aren't helping.
What were these new machines and spirits?
Honestly, I don't even know.
Going by the number of Banuk funerals I'd say the kind you turn away from.
Not really my style.
Well, if you reach my grand old age, you might prefer
picking up after hunters in the Sundom.
It's warmer too.
What is this place, "The Cut"?
When the Carja took up swords and hacked away
at the edge of Banuk land, they left The Cut behind.
So a battleground from the war, like the valley outside the Sacred Land.
Mmm-hmm. Mountain pass in the far north and east will get you there.
It's open to outlanders, hardy ones like you.
Just don't expect much of a welcome.
Especially not now.
New machines and talking spirits, I'm interested.
Thought as much just looking at you.
Don't say you weren't warned.
There's a slip of a trail through the North eastern mountains,
past what we call the Grave-Hoard.
You won't miss it.
Just keep going up until your skin starts to turn blue.
You'll find what passes for a town on the other side.
Maybe someone there can talk you out of it.
Maybe. Maybe not.
Thanks for the information.
[Carja guard]
Arrested two for disorderly conduct last night.
[Carja merchant]
You'll like what I have for sale, I promise.
[Carja artisan]
I like the sight of…
[whistle]
Ho!
This won't give me trouble anymore.
[Bandit]
We got a stiff over here!
They've taken those travellers captive.
Let's get you out of there.
I'm not leaving you in here.
[Bandit]
We're under attack!
[Bandit heavy]
Death's coming for you…!
[Nora prisoner]
…good night's rest, ready to go out hunting…
Should've brought a cart.
[Nora]
Goddess show us mercy. Do not let your faithful children be forgotten.
Sitting's underrated if you ask me.
Might need…
[Nora Brave]
Keep them guessing!
Please, help me.
[Nora Brave]
I need a little help over here.
Please, help me.
[Nora Brave]
I'd love to speak with you.
Please come, it'll only take a moment.
[Nora Brave]
I'm alive thanks to you. Please, I want you to have this.
I wouldn't have made it without you, thank you.
[whistle]
Oh, nice!
Always watching.
That was worth it.
Coming down steady as a drumbeat.
Hello!
[whistle]
Nice! To a good hunt.
[Carja outlander]
The only justice Dervahl deserves is at the tip of a spear.
[Nora Brave]
All-Mother purify the machines, cleanse them of Corruption!
Blasted Carja, the nightmares still keep me awake.
[Oseram trader]
Carja may like this heat, but I sure don't.
[Nora Brave]
My own damn fault, should've got out of there quick.
You— you can stay away!
I have no quarrel with the Nora.
And I have no quarrel with you.
These trials test a hunter's skill with different ammunition types,
when taking down machines.
Sounds easy enough.
Easy!? What do you know, girl?
I know that for someone who doesn't want to fight a Nora,
you're treading awfully close.
Now you know, so you can be on your way.
Wait, what if I wanna have a go at one of these trials?
[sighs] Then I have to give them to you.
You're not very friendly, are you?
Oh, and the Nora are? Don't you usually kill trespassers and outlanders?
Is that what you're afraid of?
Look, I didn't choose this assignment.
They told me it was an honour then stuck me right near your Sacred Lands.
So I'm keeping to what I know, herds and trials.
And hoping I won't get murdered by Nora angry about the Red Raids.
Just to be clear, I have no plans to murder you, alright?
Fine, but I'm watching you.
For this trial shoot the containers on Striders backs with fire arrows.
If you hit them right, you'll get quite a blast.
Slide down a rope so I can start timing.
You won a Blazing Sun on your first try. That's … admirable.
If you can freeze enough machines and take them down, I'll consider it a pass.
Good. I'll start timing when you slide down a rope.
So they woke up.
I've got other ammo.
I think I'm in the clear.
You won a Blazing Sun on your first try. That's … admirable.
In this trial, you'll need to stun Bellowbacks with shock ammo,
and shoot off the components in their undercarriages.
[Keeper]
Get going.
I thought they'd go on forever.
Ah, better. No more time to recover.
You won a Blazing Sun on your first try. That's … admirable.
I'm not interested in a trial right now.
Just what I wanted to hear.